Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kakowski and on this podcast I
help coaches, mentors, and trainers
scale their businesses to make more
money online. Today I want to talk about
something that I think plagues coaches
and mentors that stops them from being
able to reach the kind of people that
they want to reach. And it's something
that I notice that a lot of people
experience. It's a natural human thing.
It's a fear and a worry. You might say,
I'm not fearful or I'm not worried. I
have met the most confident people who
still experience this. It's the fear and
worry of embarrassment and humiliation.
Now before you stop this, I want you to
understand none of us would do anything
to become humiliated on purpose or to be
embarrassed on purpose. That's just
illogical. Doesn't make sense. The
problem is because we don't want to
experience those things so much. Often
times the things that are going to help
us reach the next level in our
businesses may feel like they are going
to cause us some kind of pain or
humiliation or embarrassment. And
oftentimes when it comes to whether it
be social media content, when it comes
to uh promoting your business, we let
the worry and fear of what other people
might think about us get right in the
way right in there and dictate what we
are willing to do. You got to break past
that. You got to not let the worry and
fear about what everybody else is going
to think or say about you dictate what
you are willing to do. But it's a
natural human thing. And so we got to
get to the root cause as to why this is
one of the reasons and places that this
comes from is we don't want to this goes
back to tribal human days. We don't want
to be ostracized by the tribe. If you
got embarrassed, you embarrassed the
tribe or your loyalty or your family.
You got left out. You weren't allowed to
eat which meant life or death. And so we
associate even now years later any sort
of people thinking negative things about
us as the equivalent to life or death.
That's literally in our subconscious
human
DNA. And so again, like I said, we're
not going to just do anything to become
embarrassed, to become publicly
humiliated. But let me explain something
to you. You're going to mess up. You're
going to make mistakes. You're going to
look silly. People are going
to not get it right away when you start
things out. They're going to have
opinions about what you're doing. They
may even harshly judge you. And you need
to learn to let them let them think what
they are going to think. And then let
yourself do what you need to do that you
know to do in your business. I meet so
many people and I asked them this.
Because what
if you weren't afraid of what other
people thought about you and you just
showed
up unafraid and did the thing that you
know is going to grow your bottom line.
It's going to grow your following. It's
going to grow your email list. It's
going to get people to buy from you. And
they and they were like, "Well, gosh, I
would do this, this, and this, but I
can't
because I don't want people to think XYZ
about me. I don't want them to think I'm
a salesperson. I don't want people to
think I'm I'm just in it for the money.
These are two really common ones that I
hear from a lot of mentors and coaches
because it comes from a place of I want
to help people. The problem is is
this just because like we we think that
I have this desire of I want to help
people. And so just having the desire of
I want to help people, people should
just want to be helped. They have
problems. In reality, that is not how
people respond. People actually
oftentimes don't want to be helped
because they don't want to admit that
they need to help because they don't
want to admit that they are having a
problem. And so you come out there as a
coach or a mentor or a course creator
with a solution to a problem and people
don't want to admit that they need help.
It it's embarrassing to them to admit
that. And then we're wondering, okay,
why are they not becoming a client? Why
are they not buying from us? Why are
they not purchasing when we know clearly
they need help with the thing that we
offer? And this becomes the vicious
cycle that ends up happening is
literally it's a loop between you and
your clients and all of this.
Everybody's trying to avoid
embarrassment and the pain of just
feeling like they're not good enough.
They're not enough. They're not
performing good enough. And at the end
of the day, those
things don't really
matter. They matter to the person that
you're reaching, to your prospect, to
your client. But we can't let them as
mentors and coaches matter so much to us
that we are
unwilling to actually reach and connect
with somebody. The way that you actually
get people to become your client is you
get their attention. Number one. So
that's the thing. We have to get
somebody's attention. If you can't get
somebody's
attention, you've missed out already.
And oftent times the things that get
people's attention online and on social
media, we feel like, oh, that would be
embarrassing if I did something like
that. You know, one of my best
performing ads is me just having a
little bit of fun on camera dancing like
this. It's a professional business
advertisement where I'm literally doing
a little jig on
camera. And it's amazing because it gets
the attention of the prospect that I'm
looking to reach where they read the
text that's below it. And I'm like,
"Okay, interesting.
Interesting." And I let my pride and my
ego keep me from utilizing certain types
of ad campaigns that actually performed
really well because I wanted to be Mr.
Prestigious I know everything coach
rather than prioritizing, hey, what
works, what gets people's attention and
testing things out, having fun with it.
Oftentimes, I actually found this from
my competitors. And here's another
thing. Copy your competitors. Take a
look at what are your competitors doing
for their offers and their ads. I
noticed a number of my competitors were
doing certain types of attentiongrabbing
content. It wasn't anything weird or or
anything out of the like out of the
ordinary, but it grabbed your attention
and then it had a certain call to action
to it. So, I modeled my ad campaigns. I
modeled my offers off of what are these
things that these competitors of mine
are doing that are grabbing people's
attention, the types of videos that
they're creating, the types of content
that they're doing. And you know what's
interesting? The algorithm started
picking it up. You know, oftentimes if I
post content with my kids or things like
that, it goes further, more valuable
than if it's just me sharing a profound
statement. a podcast even like
this, as powerful it is as it is,
doesn't go as far as me just dancing
around having fun with my son. And it's
amazing
because that's what people respond to.
That's what they react to. And so what I
need to do is this is not be afraid of
the judgment, the criticism, the
embarrassment of what people might think
about me and just go out there and
promote my business as best as I know
how to do in a way that I know is
actually effective. And it's powerful
when you do this, when you learn to just
let go of that. And it's and here's an
exercise that you can do mentally is
what if you just let go of all of the
identities, all of the things, all of
the versions of yourself that everybody
thinks about you, all of the versions of
yourself of how you should show up in
the world, the the shouldd
dos, what would you do? How would you
show up? What would you say? And and and
I want to challenge you to create some
content this week from that place.
putting yourself into that headsp space
before you show
up. It's powerful what happens. It's
powerful the type of connection that you
get to make to people. It's powerful
that people are actually drawn to
wanting to listen to you, to listen to
what you have to say rather than just h
maybe that's something that might be
interesting. People actually care and
they want to go deeper and further with
you. and this works. Put it to the test.
Try it out. I think you're going to be
pleasantly surprised. Listen, if you're
a coach, mentor, or trainer, I'd love to
see you in my Wealthy Coach Academy
program. It's a premier coaching
program. It's one of the number one
programs on the planet on everything
that is going to get you results
financially to become wealthy as a
mentor and coach online. And I've been
doing this in this industry for 22 years
and I can show you step by step what's
working right now today in
2025 to get results. All right
everybody, we'll talk soon. Have a good
one.
[Applause]
[Music]